ADITYA MENON

OBJECTIVE

To leverage and develop my skills and experience as a Software Developer in a job that both challenges and inspires me, while offering a Forward-Thinking & Spirited attitude with an eye for Detail and Perfection

PROFILE

Iconoclastic Software Developer with 5 years experience architecting and implementing scalable software systems. Technology has always been my burning passion and I make it a point to constantly update myself on current trends / advancements made everyday. If I were to describe myself, I would portray myself as an Developer and a Passionate Enthusiast.

EXPERIENCE

CLOUD CONSULTING ENGINEER

Armakuni Ltd - London | 2019 - 2020

CLIENTS -

• Flex/50 :-

Project Brief - To design a solution which would ingest data from various sources, scrub and store the data, infer from the cleaned data and visualise it. The visualisation would help last mile business owners to understand and optimise their business processes. Software components hosting are split between Cloud Functions and Kubernetes. Applications are packaged in Linux Docker Images for platform independent deployment

Technologies used – Golang, Python, GCP Cloud Functions, Postgres, Google Pub/Sub, Data Studio, Concourse Cl, Bitbucket, Kubernetes

• RBS :-

Project Brief – As part of the RBS DevOps cultural transformation strategy, we developed an in house tool RBS teams could use to understand their DevOps readiness and be provided with a road-map to help the team achieve their DevOps transformation goals. Application was hosted entirely on GKE with services from GCP attached (Google Pub/Sub). Applications are packaged in Linux Docker Images for platform independent deployment Technologies used – Vue.js, Typescript, Postgres, Concourse CI, Bitbucket, Kubernetes, Google Pub/Sub, Node.js (Experimented with deno JS/TS runtime engine)

- Internal Projects :-
 - Designed workshops and training modules around cloud native transformation for meetups and pre-sales client pitch
 - o Developed tools to automate processes in the SDLC. Primarily coded with Golang, Terraform and Helm
 - Helped migrate monolithic applications to microservices based solutions. Kubernetes was used to migrate stateful apps and to orchestrate them

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Cisco Systems India Pvt Ltd - Bangalore | 2017 - 2019

CLIENTS -

RISL :-

Project Brief - As part of the Indian government's smart city initiative, the Rajasthan government had brought Cisco to network the city's utilities and intelligently schedule and allocate resources across the city to reduce wastage and outages. We developed the firmware to control the edge devices and a UI to monitor and control the edge devices. IR829 applications were deployed as LXC containers and Cisco Kinetic Platform provisioned on Redhat Linux VM's via ansible

Technologies Used - Cisco IR829 (Edge Device), Cisco Kinetic Platform, C++, Yokogawa industrial sensors

• Tennessee Department of Transportation :-

Project Brief - In a bid to comply with the US federal directive of all states implementing vehicular communication infrastructure, we consulted on networking the transportation infrastructure to capture data from cars and computing at the edge to control the traffic systems and relaying data back to the traffic operations centre. IR829 applications were deployed as LXC containers and Cisco Kinetic Platform provisioned on Redhat Linux VM's via ansible

Technologies Used - Cisco IE4000 (Edge Device), Cisco Kinetic Platform, C++, Cohda Wireless Unit

• ExxonMobil :-

Project Brief - We developed a solution to monitor on oil rigs air conditions to check if SO2 levels do not breach a certain limit to prevent man down scenarios and build a map UI which would display sensor reading on the oil rig map Technologies Used - Cisco IR829 (Edge Device), Cisco Kinetic Platform, C++, Gas Leak Detection Sensors

- Internal Projects
 - o Integrate IOTA blockchain to Cisco Kinetic Platform, as a proof of concept for blockchain integration with IoT.
 - Converted monolithic application to a distributed monolith by hosting software components on fat docker containers and orchestrated on Kubernetes
 - Design PCB to interface sensors with IR829 and IE4000 edge devices
 - R&D project to test IR829 docker images without physical hardware to ease the testing cycle and enable CI/CD integration

CO-FOUNDER & PRODUCT DEVELOPER

AnonyByte - Bangalore | 2014 - 2016

- Founded start-up focusing on home automation and security
- Operated the company on the Lean Startup principles which helped fine tune hypothesis and product assumptions
- Designed modules and routers with PLC (Powerline communication) for zero configuration setup and simplistic user experience
- Developed PCB design and firmware (C based) for product lines
- Handled marketing and sales function for company
- Designed and maintained company cloud infrastructure on AWS
- Applications (based on Python3) hosted on EC2 instances were provisioned with Arch Linux as base OS via Ansible

Technologies used - AWS EC2, CloudFormation, C, Python, Fritzing (PCB Design), Route 53, BASH, Linux, Ansible

CERTIFICATION

CERTIFIED CISCO NETWORK ASSOCIATE - CERTIFICATION

Cisco | 2018

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

PESIT | 2013 - 2017

HOBBIES

- Hardcore UNIX & Linux aficionado. Created distros based on the Linux kernel and FreeBSD
- Active member of the XDA Dev community
- Supporter of the Open Source Software movement
- ARM based System hobbyist
- Design Android ROMs and Recovery for devices
- Tech Enthusiast
- Dabbling in blockchain technologies viz Solidity in Ethereum, Qubic in IOTA

LANGUAGES

- Python
- Go
- C, C++
- Kotlin/Java
- BASH
- SQL

PLATFORMS / TOOLS

- UNIX OS
- Android SDK & AOSP
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- PostgreSQL, NoSQL
- Git
- Distributed Systems
- Blockchain
- Terraform
- Kubernetes

CONTACT

Mobile: +91 9036019395 / +44 7957958957 Email ID: adityamenon5@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/adityamenon5</u>